Guide to the Newton Taylor Collection, 1941-1963
Department of Special Collections
Newton Taylor Collection,
1941-1963
Special Collections M0195
Taylor, Newton.
4 folders
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Professor Ray R. Birdwhistell, 1969.
Scope and content
Letters written to Newton Taylor in regard to research he was doing on the life of Clyde Fitch. He was planning to write a book about the life of Fitch, but apparently it was never written. Also includes miscellaneous printed material, typed notes, and a typescript by Taylor.
Container List
- BLANCHARD, ARTHUR F. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 28., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, June 3., A.L.S. to N.T.
- BLANCHARD, CHARLES B. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 5., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, May 10., T.L.S. to N.T.
- BRADY, WILLIAM A. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 24., T.L.S. to N.T.
- CANE, MELVILLE H. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 8., T.L.S. to N.T.
- CARTER, MORRIS (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 3. T.L.S. to N.T. with enclosure of postcard giving hours of the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum.
- COLLINGE, PATRICIA (Folder 1)
  - 1941, Oct. 23., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, Oct. 24., A.L.S. to N.T.
- DOYLE, NAN BRUCE (Folder 1)
  - 1941, June 4., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1942, March 26., A.L.S. to N.T.
- DYAR, RALPH E. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, Sept. 26., T.L.S. to N.T.
- EMERY, GILBERT (Folder 1)
  - EMERY, GILBERT, March 11., A.L.S. to N.T. (Folder 1)
  - EMERY, GILBERT, Nov. 13., A.N.S. to [N.T.] (Folder 1)
- FASH, WILLIAM G. (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 13., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, May 26., T.L.S. to N.T.
- FLANAGAN, J. ARTHUR (Folder 1)
  - 1941, May 8., A.L.S. & cvr. to N.T.
- FURNESS, CLIFTON JOSEPH (Folder 1)
  - 1941, April 28., T.L.S. to N.T.
- GERSON, VIRGINIA (Folder 1)
  - 1941, July 12., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, July 16., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, Aug. 3., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, Sept. 26., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, Nov. 18., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, Dec. 5., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Monday., A.N.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Monday., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Monday., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Monday Night., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Tuesday., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Wednesday., A.N.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., Friday., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., A.N.S. to N.T.
- GILDER, RODMAN
  - 1942, March 3., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
- MAPES, JULIA PIERSON (Folder 2)
  - n.d., A.L.S. to N.T.
- MARCOSSON, ISAAC F. (Folder 2)
  - 1941, May 9. T.L.S. to N.T., followed by a report by Taylor on a phone conversation with Marcosson on May 12.
  - MARCOSSON, ISAAC F., June 2., A.N.S. to N.T.
  - MARCOSSON, ISAAC F., June 3., A.N.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., A.N.S. to N.T.
- MAUGHAM, W.S. (Folder 2)
  - 1941, May 22., T.N.S. to N.T.
- MERINGTON, MARGUERITE (Folder 2)
  - 1941, June 4., A.N.S. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, June 11., T.N. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, July 14., T.N. (postcard) to N.T.
  - 1941, Nov. 22., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1942, Jan. 11., T.N.S. to N.T.
  - 1942, Jan. 21., T.N. (postcard) to N.T.
- MITCHELL, GRANT (Folder 2)
  - 1941, Sept. 10., Telegram to N.T.
  - [1941] Sept. 15., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - [1941,Sept. 16], A.L.S. to N.T.
  - [1941, Sept.]21., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - [1941, Sept.]22., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - [1941] Oct. 12. A.L.S. to Virginia [Gerson]
- MOORE, PERCY T[UNK] (Folder 2)
  - 1943, Jan. 18. T.L.S. to Grant Mitchell with note on top by Mitchell.
- POLLOCK, CHANNING (Folder 2)
  - 1941, May 19., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, May 29., T.N.S. to N.T.
- RAND, JERRY (Folder 3)
  - n.d., T.L.S. to N.T.
- SAMORINI, ARNALDO A. (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 23., T.L.S. to N.T.
- SEYMOUR, MAY DAVENPORT (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 14., T.L.S. to N.T.
- SKINNER, OTIS (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 24., A.L.S. to N.T.
- TAYLOR, ROBERT (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 6., T.L.S. to N.T.
- TOWNE, CHARLES HANSON (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 14., T.L.S. to N.T.
- WHITMAN, FRANK E. (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 17., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, May 27., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, Oct. 5., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, Oct. 27., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - 1941, Nov. 5., A.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d. A.L.S. & cvr. to Mrs. Alice Muller-Thym introducing Newton Taylor.
- WILSTACH, JOHN (Folder 3)
  - 1941, May 25., T.L.S. to N.T.
  - n.d., T.L.S. to N.T.
- MISCELLANEOUS (Folder 4)
  - Gordon, Caroline, A Good Soldier, University of California Library, Davis, 1963.
  - Photograph of Clyde Fitch (torn from a book)
  - Preface to Beau Brummell from Longer Plays by Modern Authors.
  - Stage Souvenirs of Frohman Seen, New York Times, May 8, 1941.
  - [Taylor,Newton] The Fun of Writing a Book About Clyde Fitch, (typescript)
  - [Taylor,Newton], 6 pages of typed notes.
  - Unidentified Correspondence
    - a. n.d. A.L.S. from Aspasia [Pam ___] to Dear Young Friend.
    - b. 1942, July 28., T.L.S. from Harry to N.T.
    - c. n.d. A.N.S., (postcard) to Mr. & Mrs. Natby.